Guide to the Scoville Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Scoville Family Papers
1797-2002
MS 2045
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.67
(14 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, speeches, diaries, clippings, printed matter, and other papers related to descendants of Samuel Scoville, Sr. (1835-1902) and his wife Harriet Eliza Beecher (1838-1911). Materials document the activities of members of the Beecher, Gallaudet, Scoville, Trumbull, and Barry families. The bulk of the material relates to Alice Scoville Barry's research on Henry Ward Beecher, particularly on the 1875 adultery trial against Theodore Tilton and his wife Elizabeth Tilton. Her research notes include her opinions, book drafts, and correspondence with family members and close friends, including her brother Reverend Gurdon Trumbull Scoville (1904-1993). Additionally, the papers include materials relating to deaf education from Thomas Hopkins Gallaudet, Gallaudet genealogical information, writings, and family photographs. Also included are letters between Trumbull family members, biographical articles and obituaries of the Trumbull family, society applications with genealogical information, photographs, and newspaper clippings. Most of the Trumbull family correspondence is among Henry Clay Trumbull, Sally Ann Swan, James Hammond, Gurdon Trumbull, Sr., Gurdon Trumbull, Jr. and other family members. The collection also includes genealogical charts, sermons of Henry Ward Beecher and his father, Lyman Beecher, family correspondence, diaries of Harriet Eliza Beecher Scoville, and Samuel Scoville, Sr., and family photographs.
Scoville family
Barry, Alice Trumbull Scoville
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in five series: I. Beecher Family Papers. II. Gallaudet Family Papers. III. Scoville Family Papers. IV. Trumbull Family Papers. V. Anne Scoville Barry Research Materials.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, speeches, diaries, clippings, printed matter, and other papers related to descendants of Samuel Scoville, Sr. (1835-1902) and his wife Harriet Eliza Beecher (1838-1911). Materials document the activities of members of the Beecher, Gallaudet, Scoville, Trumbull, and Barry families.
The bulk of the material relates to Alice Scoville Barry's research on Henry Ward Beecher, particularly on the 1875 adultery trial against Theodore Tilton and his wife Elizabeth Tilton. Her research notes include her opinions, book drafts, and correspondence with family members and close friends, including her brother Reverend Gurdon Trumbull Scoville (1904-1993).
Additionally, the papers include materials relating to deaf education from Thomas Hopkins Gallaudet, Gallaudet genealogical information, writings, and family photographs.
Also included are letters between Trumbull family members, biographical articles and obituaries of the Trumbull family, society applications with genealogical information, photographs, and newspaper clippings. Most of the Trumbull family correspondence is among Henry Clay Trumbull, Sally Ann Swan, James Hammond, Gurdon Trumbull, Sr., Gurdon Trumbull, Jr. and other family members.
The collection also includes genealogical charts, sermons of Henry Ward Beecher and his father, Lyman Beecher, family correspondence, diaries of Harriet Eliza Beecher Scoville, and Samuel Scoville, Sr., and family photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Reverend Samuel Scoville, Sr. was a clergyman married to Harriet Eliza Beecher, daughter of Reverend Henry Ward Beecher and Eunice White (Bullard) Beecher. Henry Ward Beecher was a clergyman known for his leadership and support of women's suffrage and the abolition of slavery, and was the brother of author and suffragist Harriet Beecher Stowe.
Samuel Scoville, Jr. (1872-1950, Yale 1893), son of Samuel Scoville, Sr. and Harriet Eliza Beecher, graduated from Yale College and earned a law degree from the University of the State of New York in 1895, subsequently becoming an attorney, novelist, ornithologist, and author of a Boy Scout series of chapter books for young readers. He married Katharine Gallaudet, the grand-daughter of Thomas Hopkins Gallaudet.
The Gallaudet family included Thomas Hopkins Gallaudet (1787-1851, Yale 1805), founder and head of the American School for the Deaf in West Hartford, Connecticut, 1817-1830, and an early figure in deaf mute instruction in America. He and his wife Sophia Fowler Gallaudet had eight children, which included Alice Cogswell (Gallaudet) Trumbull (1833-1891), named in honor of the student who inspired him to establish the school for the deaf.
Alice Cogswell Gallaudet married Henry Clay Trumbull (1830-1903), a clergyman and author, an advocate for Sunday School education, and one of ten children to Gurdon Trumbull, Sr. and Sarah Swan Trumbull. His siblings included James Hammond Trumbull, philologist, and Gurdon Trumbull, Jr., ornithologist and illustrator. The children of Henry Clay Trumbull and Alice Gallaudet were descendants of Elder William Brewster, who was a founder of the Plymouth Colony in 1620, as well as Reverend Thomas Hooker, who is recognized as one of the founders of Connecticut.
Samuel and Katharine Scoville's children included Alice Trumbull (Scoville) Barry (1911-2012), an author and educator. She graduated from Vassar College in 1933 and shortly thereafter married Stuyvesant Peter Barry. Later in life, she wrote a local newspaper column in Pennsylvania, taught remedial reading, and wrote a biography of her great-grandfather, Henry Ward Beecher.
Genealogical information was sourced mainly from society applications filled in by Alice Gallaudet (Trumbull) Sparhawk, daughter of Henry Clay and Alice Cogswell (Gallaudet) Trumbull, as well as other research notes in the Scoville Family Papers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Roxana Barry Robinson in memory of Gurdon Trumbull Scoville, William Beecher Scoville and Alice Trumbull Scoville Barry, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Related Materials
Related material: Beecher Family Papers (MS 71).
Sermons; Adultery; Women -- Suffrage; Genealogies; Scoville family
- Beecher Family Papers, 1806-1898
  Scope and Contents
  This series comprises photographs, sermons, correspondence, and printed materials regarding Beecher family members.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by family member.
  - Beecher, Henry Ward
    - Article by Phillips Brooks, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Autobiographical Reminiscences of Henry Ward Beecher, edited by T. J. Ellinwood, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "His Life, as Sketched by the Rev. Henry Ward Beecher Himself," report on speech given in London, 28 September, 1886 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript notes on sermons, 1858-1860, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Letter from Henry Ward Beecher to unidentified recipient, typescript, 1874 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Photograph of Henry Ward Beecher, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Plymouth Pulpit: A Weekly Publication of Sermons Preached by Henry Ward Beecher, #7, 9-11, 20, 25, 1869–1875 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sermons by Henry Ward Beecher in Two Volumes, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - "Wendell Phillips: A Commemorative Discourse", 1884 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Beecher, Lyman, "A Sermon, Containing a General History of the Town of East Hampton, (L.I.) from Its First Settlement to the Present Time", 1806 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stowe, Harriet Beecher
    - Articles about Harriet Beecher Stowe, 1897-1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Letter to Henry Ward Beecher, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Sunny Memories of Foreign Lands, volume 1, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Gallaudet Family Papers, 1828-1984
  This series comprises correspondence, genealogical information, and printed materials related to the Gallaudet family.
  This series is arranged into general materials, then alphabetically by family member.
  - General
    - The American Era, American School of the Deaf, 1943–1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - The American School of the Deaf, West Hartford, Connecticut, brochure, Circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings related to Thomas Gallaudet, 1898–1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "The Education of the Deaf," by Edmund B. Boatner, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Founders' Memorial dedication exercises, American School for the Deaf and New England Gallaudet Association of the Deaf, 1953 April 18 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "Gallaudet: Famous Name and Forgotten Indiana Town," by Sylvia C. Henricks, 1984 May (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Photographs of Gallaudet family members, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gallaudet, P. W., letter to Sophia Fowler Gallaudet, 1838 August 6 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gallaudet, Sophia, memorial brochure by Amos G. Draper, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gallaudet, Thomas, 75 Years Old poem read at a family dinner at the home of son-in-law Alex D. Shaw, 1897 June 3 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gallaudet, Thomas Hopkins
    - Family genealogical information, 1949, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Note from Thomas H. Gallaudet, 1846 August 21 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "A Statement with Regard to the Moorish Prince, Abduhl Rahhahman", 1828 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Syles, Henry Winter, "A Biographical Sketch of the Rev. Thomas Hopkins Gallaudet, LL.D., the First Great Educator of the Deaf in America", 1887 December (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Scoville Family Papers, 1861-1942
  This series comprises diaries, printed materials, and correspondence.
  - Scoville, Harriet Eliza Beecher, diary, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Scoville, Samuel Sr.
    - "A Christian View of Popular Amusements", 1881 November (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper clippings regarding Samuel Scoville, Sr., 1894–1902 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Commentaries on "Reminiscences of Henry Ward Beecher and Harriet Beecher Stowe", 1899-1900, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and notes on funeral of Mr. George Parks, 1861–1900 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Development of the Organic Life in the Congregational Church", 1888 April (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Diaries
      - 1864–1866 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - 1867–1897 (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
    - Engraving of Samuel Scoville, Sr., by A. H. Ritchie, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Memorial Services in Honor of Father Beecher, Held in the Congregational Church, Stamford, Connecticut," manuscript, 1887 March 13 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Recollections of Harriet Beecher Stowe," typescript, annotated, Circa 1890s (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Reminiscences of Henry Ward Beecher and Harriet Beecher Stowe", Circa 1890s (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Drafts, notes, and partial versions (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Typescript, annotated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "The 75th Anniversary of the Building of the Meeting House at North Cornwall of the 2d Ecclesiastical Society in Cornwall, and Service in Memory of the Rev. Samuel Scoville, August 24, 1902", 1904 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "Talk Concerning Rev. H.W. Beecher and Mrs. Harriet Beecher Stowe, May 20," manuscript, Circa 1890s (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "What Made Henry Ward Beecher a Great Man", 1902 August 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Scoville, Samuel Jr.
    - Seven Mountains, typescript, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 4-7)
    - "War and the Law", 1942 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Trumbull Family Papers, 1797-1978
  This series comprises genealogical charts, correspondence, and photographs of Trumbull family members.
  The series is arranged by general materials, then alphabetically by family member.
  - General
    - Correspondence concerning family genealogy, 1845–1880 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Genealogical charts, 1875, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "History of the Trumbull Family" clipping, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of Trumbull family members, Circa 1860-circa 1950 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Photograph of Henry Clay Trumbull, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Slosson, Annie Trumbull, biographical articles, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sparhawk, Alice Gallaudet Trumbull
    - Applications to societies, with genealogical information, 1905–1907 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Photographs and genealogy, Circa 1895 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sparhawk, John, correspondence on Trumbull family genealogy, 1907 July-August (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Swan, Tommy, letter to Fanny Palmer concerning his miniature, 1797 June 16 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Trumbull, Annie, correspondence, 1870-1871, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Trumbull, Annie Elliot
    - Clippings, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Obituary, 1949 January 22 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Trumbull, Charles, letter to brother, 1853 November 14 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Trumbull, Gurdon, Sr.
    - Correspondence, 1847, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence to Sarah "Sally" Ann Swan Trumbull, 1818, 1828, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Portrait of Gurdon Trumbull," by Ane Bentz, 1978 November (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Trumbull, Gurdon, Jr.
    - Correspondence to Alice Trumbull Sparhawk, 1902 June 19 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence to Major Thomas Trumbull, 1864 August 13-October 11 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "Our Scoters", 1893 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Trumbull, Henry Clay
    - Correspondence from Fanny Noyes, his grandmother, 1839, 1851 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence from Reverend Maltie Babcock, 1896 February 24 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence to wife, Alice Cogswell, 1891 August (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Diary, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "A Helper in Every Sphere" clipping, Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "How to Help a Pupil to See Jesus" galley sheet, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Litchfield County Connecticut or One Rural County's Contributions to the Nation's Power and Fame" brochure, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Trumbull, James Hammond
    - Clippings, 1897, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence from family members, 1828–1849 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence from Fanny Noyes, his grandmother, 1839 December 20 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "The Defence of Stonington (Connecticut) Against a British Squadron, August 9th to 12th, 1814", 1864 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Engley, Donald B., "James Hammond Trumbull, Bibliographer of Connecticut", 1954 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Obituaries, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Trumbull, S. Anna, "The Attack upon Stonington" manuscript, Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Trumbull, Sarah "Sally" Ann obituary, 1879 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Unidentified author, copy of a letter to the Governor of Connecticut on the election of the President of the United States, 1812 September 12 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Alice Scoville Barry Research Papers, 1870-2002
  This series comprises research notes created by Alice Scoville Barry, and Barry and Beecher family memorabilia. Barry's research notes for an apparently unpublished biography titled The Trial of Henry Ward Beecher constitute the largest series in the collection and include her notes on her opinions, book drafts, and correspondence with family members and close friends, including her brother Reverend Gurdon Trumbull Scoville (1904-1993). Barry's notes are often fragmentary but are extensively labeled to detail testimonies, themes, events, and press coverage of the Tilton adultery trial.
  Materials are generally arranged in accordance with the original order maintained by Barry, with the exception of cases that necessitated rearrangement by Manuscripts and Archives staff to facilitate ease of access. Some notes were refiled in chronological order or with a relevant existing grouping
  Conditions Governing Access
  Any requests, including by Yale, to make copies of the unpublished biography of Henry Ward Beecher by Alice Trumbull Scoville Barry using any medium, format, or technology now in existence or hereinafter devised, to upload such copies of the Property to the Internet or like media, or to publish any parts of the Property shall be directed to Roxana Barry Robinson or her daughter.
  - Writings
    - The Trial of Henry Ward Beecher
      - Manuscript, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
      - Title page, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Book cover mockup, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Drafted pages
        - #3 Henry Ward Beecher's speech to the Copperheads, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 3)
        - #4 Henry Ward Beecher and Abraham Lincoln, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 4)
        - #5 Firing on Fort Sumter, beginning of the war April 12, 1861, pages 61-83, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 5)
        - #6 Investigating committee report, dated 1874 August 27, and Beecher-Tilton investigation pamphlet, circa 1874, photocopies, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 6)
        - #7 Elizabeth's Last Statement, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 7)
        - #11 Henry Ward Beecher letter to Eunice Beecher, copy, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 8)
        - #16 Elizabeth's Secret, with edits, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 9)
        - #17 Henry Ward Beecher on the Woman's Vote, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 10)
        - #18 Fugitive Slave Law, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 11)
        - #19 Harriet B. Stowe and Conversation with Elizabeth Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 12)
        - #20 End of War, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 13)
        - #21 Bowen against Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 14)
        - #22 Henry Ward Beecher's Chronology, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 15)
        - #23 His Lecture-tour after the trial, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 16)
        - #24 Victoria Woodhull, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 17)
        - #24 Victoria Woodhull -- Hell Hath No Fury, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 18)
        - Pages 1-119, master copy, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 19)
        - Pages 1-80, 236-242, sent to Gurdon [Trumbull?], Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 20)
        - Pages 7-9, 180-452, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 21)
        - Pages 22-114, 147-179, master copy, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 22)
        - Pages 105-299, with comments from others, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 23)
        - Pages 126-213, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 24)
        - Pages 160-195, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 25)
        - Pages 202-368, 436-473, sent to Burton [Powers], with correspondence and notes, 1988 Feb 8-1990 Feb 3 (Box 8, Folder 26)
        - Pages 217-377, part II beginning with Donner's letter "Tilton is no friend of yours" April 22, 1865, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 27)
        - Pages 234-299, 1988–1989 (Box 8, Folder 28)
        - Pages 249-307, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 29)
        - Pages 368-473, sent to Gurdon Scoville, 1989 December 12 (Box 8, Folder 30)
        - Pages 379-560, part III, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 31)
        - Pages 389-520, master copy, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 32)
        - Pages 432-610, to Gurdon [Scoville] and Burton [Powers], Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - Pages 453-716, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Pages 490-632, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Page 520, copy of letter of contrition, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Pages 541-551, unidentified pages, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Pages 545-575, notes, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - Pages 570-978, master copy, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Pages 600-602, Roxana [Barry]'s suggestions, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Pages 633-634, 654-802, master copy, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Pages 752-822, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - Pages 888-974, copy by [Peter Barry?], Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - Page 1017 to ending, volume III, handwritten draft, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - Volume II notes, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - Duplicate pages, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 14)
        - Comments, to do lists, 1986 Jan 9-1988 Nov, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Henry Ward Beecher: Saint or Sinner?, by Alice Scoville Barry
      - Two copies of published pamphlet, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - #26 Pamphlet draft, including Elizabeth's statement, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Draft, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Draft sent to Carol with other unidentified writings, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Beecher and Tilton Reappraised, by Alice Scoville Barry
      - Part I, Master Copy pp. 1-216, through Lincoln's assassination and funeral, with references, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Draft, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Speeches
      - Stowe-Day Library, 1983 October 13 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Unidentified speech transcript, 1983 October (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - England and Edinburgh, Scotland, fragments, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Alice Scoville Barry's speech, as taped by P.B. [Peter Barry?], Circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Why Did President Lincoln Suppress the Journal of Commerce? (4 copies), Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Research files
    - Henry Ward Beecher
      - Woodhull and Claflin's Weekly, photocopy, 1872 November 2 (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Speech in Glasgow, Scotland, Patriotic Address in America and England, from 1850 to 1885, on Slavery, the Civil War, and the Development of Civil Liberty in the United States, by Henry Ward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Seven Lectures to Young Men, on various important subjects, by Henry Ward Beecher, photocopy, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - #1 Lectures to Young Men, 1843-1844, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Draft, The Passion of Henry Ward Beecher, a television play by Martin Halpern, Circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Quest Magazine, letters to the editor from Alice Scoville Barry, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - Quest Magazine issues, 1988 September-1989 February (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Henry Ward Beecher grave information, 1994 October 16 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Seven Lectures to Young Men on Various Important Subjects, copy with notes, 1997 October 22 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Beecher-Tilton trial notes
      Files include original material by Anne Scoville Barry and working drafts of her unpublished biography of Henry Ward Beecher.
      - Testimonies
        - Eunice Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Theodore Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 4-6)
        - Frank Moulton, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 7)
        - Henry Ward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 8)
        - Charles Storrs, April 1, 1875, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 9)
        - Henry Bowen, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 10)
        - Samuel Wilkeson tripartite agreement and commission for Beecher's son Harry, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 11)
        - Henry Ward Beecher, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 12)
        - Charles Cowley, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 13)
        - Mrs. Mitchell, Elizabeth Tilton's nurse, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 14)
        - Abbott J. Holliday, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 15)
        - Mrs. Mitchell in trial, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 16)
        - Henry Ward Beecher, cross examination, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 17)
        - Bessie Turner, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 18)
        - James Woodley and two unidentified African American servants of Victoria Woodhull, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 19)
        - Ladder-Price affidavits, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 20)
        - Henry Bowen, testimony and cross examination, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 21)
        - Henry M. Cleveland and Thomas J. Turner, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 22)
        - Emma Moulton, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 23)
        - Jury, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 24)
        - Notes on lawyers, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 25)
        - Emma Moulton, cross examination, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 26)
        - Francis D. Carpenter, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 27)
        - James Redpath, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 28)
        - Note on alleged letter: Henry Ward Beecher to Elizabeth, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth Tilton, Circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 30)